Contact

gregdarcy01@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/gregdarcy (LinkedIn) www.esa.edu.au/projects/ australian-curriculum-connect (Company)

Top Skills

Project Management
Analytics
Research Data Management

Certifications

edX Verified Certificate for Introduction to Cloud Infrastructure Technologies

Greg D'Arcy

Analytics | Data Science | Project Management | eResearch Greater Melbourne Area

Summary

I am a highly experienced digital professional having worked in a range of roles such as digital project management, data analytics, website development, online communications and training within the research and education sectors. I possess strong communication and organisational skills with a strong attention to detail and the ability to juggle complex and competing priorities. My core strengths are based on managing client expectations and building strong client relationships.

Experience

The University of Melbourne Research Data Analyst/Platform Administrator March 2016 - Present (5 years 2 months)

In my current role I provide expert advice and support to academics and researchers in the Humanities, Arts and Social Sciences on on the use of research software and data management in their research.

Writer's Web Communications
Consultant
June 1997 - March 2016 (18 years 10 months)

Personal consultancy services in content development, online marketing and web development.

La Trobe University
Project Manager, Major Open Data Collections
October 2014 - December 2015 (1 year 3 months)

I managed a nationally funded research project that produced a Population Health data collection focused on cardiovascular disease. I provided executive support to a working group of senior staff and researchers to draft the policies and procedures for managing Research Data and Primary Materials in accordance the Australian Code for the Responsible Conduct of Research (2007).

Education Services Australia Senior Project Manager June 2005 - July 2014 (9 years 2 months)

I have managed complex digital content projects to support the implementation of the Australian curriculum across education jurisdictions. I managed over 50 projects with Australian cultural organizations and government agencies, providing advice on copyright and licencing, metadata standards, Accessibility and Quality Assurance.

Monash University

Lecturer

January 2005 - November 2006 (1 year 11 months)

I prepared and delivered lectures and tutorials for under-graduate and postgraduate students in Advanced Multimedia.

RMIT University

Lecturer

January 2004 - June 2006 (2 years 6 months)

I prepared and delivered lectures and tutorials for under-graduate and post-graduate students in Strategic Communications Management, Web Development and Applications, and Digital publishing.

Australian Taxation Office

Web Content Manager

November 2003 - July 2004 (9 months)

I was part of a project to audit of the ATO intranet that required mapping As-Is and To-Be business processes and delivering approved process improvements.

The Salvation Army

Employment Program Manager

February 2002 - September 2003 (1 year 8 months)

I managed the Brunswick Division's New Start employment and training program in web design and office skills.

Education

RMIT University

Master of Technology (M.Tech.), Internet & Web Computing · (2003 - 2006)

University of South Australia

Professional Certificate in Web Accessibility, Web Accessibility · (2015 - 2015)

Queensland University of Technology

Master of Business, Online Communucations · (1996 - 1998)

Deakin University

Bachelor's degree, Journalism, Literature, Anthropology · (1990 - 1992)

Chadstone High